在以前的视频中我们谈到
In previous videos, we talked
关于梯度下降算法
about the gradient descent algorithm
梯度下降是很常用的算法 它不仅被用在线性回归上
and talked about the linear
和线性回归模型、平方误差代价函数
regression model and the squared error cost function.
在这段视频中  我们要
In this video, we're going to
将梯度下降
put together gradient descent with
和代价函数结合
our cost function, and that
在后面的视频中 我们将用到此算法 并将其应用于
will give us an algorithm for
具体的拟合直线的线性回归算法里
linear regression for fitting a straight line to our data.
这就是
So, this is
我们在之前的课程里所做的工作
what we worked out in the previous videos.
这是梯度下降法
That's our gradient descent algorithm, which
这个算法你应该很熟悉
should be familiar, and you
这是线性回归模型
see the linear linear regression model
还有线性假设和平方误差代价函数
with our linear hypothesis and our squared error cost function.
我们将要做的就是
What we're going to do is apply
用梯度下降的方法
gradient descent to minimize
来最小化平方误差代价函数
our squared error cost function.
为了
Now, in order to apply
使梯度下降 为了
gradient descent, in order
写这段代码
to write this piece of
我们需要的关键项
code, the key term
是这里这个微分项
we need is this derivative term over here.
所以.我们需要弄清楚
So, we need to figure out
这个偏导数项是什么
what is this partial derivative term,
并结合这里的
and plug in the
代价函数J
definition of the cost
的定义
function J, this turns
就是这样
out to be this "inaudible"
一个求和项
equals sum 1 through M of
代价函数就是
this squared error
这个误差平方项
cost function term, and all
我这样做 只是
I did here was I just
把定义好的代价函数
you know plugged in the definition of
插入了这个微分式
the cost function there, and simplifying
再简化一下
little bit more, this turns
这等于是
out to be equal to, this
这一个求和项
"inaudible" equals sum 1 through M
θ0 + θ1x(1) - y(i)
of tetha zero plus tetha one, XI
minus YI squared.
这一项其实就是
And all I did there was took
我的假设的定义
the definition for my hypothesis
然后把这一项放进去
and plug that in there.
实际上我们需要
And it turns out we need
弄清楚这两个
to figure out what is
偏导数项是什么
the partial derivative of two
这两项分别是 j=0
cases for J equals
和j=1的情况
0 and for J equals 1 want
因此我们要弄清楚
to figure out what is this
θ0 和 θ1 对应的
partial derivative for both the
偏导数项是什么
theta(0) case and the theta(1) case.
我只把答案写出来
And I'm just going to write out the answers.
事实上 第一项可简化为
It turns out this first term simplifies
1 / m 乘以求和式
to 1/M, sum over
对所有训练样本求和
my training set of just
求和项是 h(x(i))-y(i)
that, X(i)-  Y(i).
而这一项
And for this term, partial derivative
对θ(1)的微分项
with respect to theta(1), it turns
得到的是这样一项
out I get this term: -Y(i)X(i).
对吧
Okay.
计算出这些
And computing these partial
偏导数项
derivatives, so going from
从这个等式
this equation to either
到下面的等式
of these equations down there, computing
计算这些偏导数项需要一些多元微积分
those partial derivative terms requires some multivariate calculus.
如果你掌握了微积分
If you know calculus, feel free
你可以随便自己推导这些
to work through the derivations yourself
然后你检查你的微分
and check take the derivatives
你实际上会得到我给出的答案
you actually get the answers that I got.
但如果你
But if you are less
不太熟悉微积分
familiar with calculus you don't
别担心
worry about it, and it
你可以直接用这些
is fine to just take these equations
已经算出来的结果
worked out, and you
你不需要掌握微积分
won't need to know calculus or
或者别的东西
anything like that in order to
来完成作业 你只需要会用梯度下降就可以
do the homework, so to implement gradient descent you'd get that to work.
在定义这些以后
But so, after these definitions,
在我们算出
or after what we've worked
这些微分项以后
out to be the derivatives, which
这些微分项
is really just the slope of
实际上就是代价函数J的斜率
the cost function J.  We
现在可以将它们放回
can now plug them back into
我们的梯度下降算法
our gradient descent algorithm.
所以这就是专用于
So here's gradient descent, or
线性回归的梯度下降
the regression, which is going
反复执行括号中的式子直到收敛
to repeat until convergence, theta 0
θ0和θ1不断被更新
and theta one get updated as,
都是加上一个-α/m
you know, the same minus alpha
乘上后面的求和项
times the derivative term.
所以这里这一项
So, this term here.
所以这就是我们的线性回归算法
So, here's our linear regression algorithm.
这里的第一项
This first term here that
当然
term is, of course, just
这一项就是关于θ0的偏导数
a partial derivative of respective
在上一张幻灯片中推出的
theta zero, that we worked on in the previous slide.
而第二项
And this second term here,
这一项是刚刚的推导出的
that term is just
关于θ1的
a partial derivative with respect to
偏导数项
theta one that we worked out on the previous line.
提醒一下
And just as a quick reminder,
执行梯度下降时
you must, when implementing gradient descent,
有一个细节要注意
there's actually there's detail that, you
就是必须要
know, you should be implementing
同时更新θ0和θ1
it so the update theta zero and theta one simultaneously.
所以 让我们来看看梯度下降是如何工作的
So, let's see how gradient descent works.
我们用梯度下降解决问题的
One of the issues we solved
一个原因是 它更容易得到局部最优值
gradient descent is that it can be susceptible to local optima.
当我第一次解释梯度下降时
So, when I first explained gradient
我展示过这幅图
descent, I showed you this picture
在表面上
of it, you know, going downhill
不断下降
on the surface and we
并且我们知道了
saw how, depending on where
根据你的初始化 你会得到不同的局部最优解
you're initializing, you can end up with different local optima.
你知道.你可以结束了.在这里或这里。
You know, you can end up here or here.
但是 事实证明
But, it turns out that
用于线性回归的
the cost function for gradient
代价函数
of cost function for linear regression
总是这样一个
is always going to be
弓形的样子
a bow-shaped function like this.
这个函数的专业术语是
The technical term for this
这是一个凸函数
is that this is called a convex function.
我不打算在这门课中
And I'm not going
给出凸函数的定义
to give the formal definition for what
凸函数(convex function)
is a convex function, c-o-n-v-e-x, but
但不正式的说法是
informally a convex function
它就是一个弓形的函数
means a bow-shaped function, you know, kind of like a bow shaped.
因此 这个函数
And so, this function doesn't
没有任何局部最优解
have any local optima, except
只有一个全局最优解
for the one global optimum.
并且无论什么时候
And does gradient descent on
你对这种代价函数
this type of cost function which
使用线性回归
you get whenever you're using linear
梯度下降法得到的结果
regression, it will always convert
总是收敛到全局最优值 因为没有全局最优以外的其他局部最优点
to the global optimum, because there are no other local optima other than global optimum.
现在 让我们来看看这个算法的执行过程
So now, let's see this algorithm in action.
像往常一样
As usual, here are plots of
这是假设函数的图
the hypothesis function and of
还有代价函数J的图
my cost function J.
让我们来看看如何
And so, let's see how
初始化参数的值
to initialize my parameters at this value.
通常来说
You know, let's say, usually you
初始化参数为零
initialize your parameters at zero
θ0和θ1都在零
for zero, theta zero and zero.
但为了展示需要
For illustration in this
在这个梯度下降的实现中
specific presentation, I have
我把θ0初始化为-900
initialised theta zero at
θ1初始化为-0.1
about 900, and theta one at about minus 0.1, okay?
这对应的假设
And so, this corresponds to H
就应该是这样
over X, equals, you know,
h(x)是等于-900减0.1x
minus 900 minus 0.1 x
这对应我们的代价函数
is this line, so out here on the cost function.
现在 如果我们进行
Now if we take one
一次梯度下降
step of gradient descent, we end
从这个点开始
up going from this point
在这里.一点点
out here, a little
向左下方移动了一小步
bit to the down left
这就得到了第二个点
to that second point over there.
而且你注意到这条线改变了一点点
And, you notice that my line changed a little bit.
然后我再进行
And, as I take another step
一步梯度下降 左边这条线又变一点
at gradient descent, my line on the left will change.
对吧
Right.
同样地
And I have also
我又移到代价函数上的另一个点
moved to a new point on my cost function.
再进行一步梯度下降
And as I think further step
我觉得我的代价项
is gradient descent, I'm going
应该开始下降了
down in cost, right, so
所以我的参数是
my parameter is following
跟随着这个轨迹
this trajectory, and if
再看左边这个图
you look on the left, this corresponds
这个表示的是假设函数h(x)
to hypotheses that seem
它变得好像
to be getting to be
越来越拟合数据
better and better fits for the
直到它渐渐地
data until eventually,
收敛到全局最小值
I have now wound up at the global minimum.
这个全局最小值
And this global minimum corresponds to
对应的假设函数 给出了最拟合数据的解
this hypothesis, which gives me a good fit to the data.
这就是梯度下降法
And so that's gradient
我们刚刚运行了一遍
descent, and we've just run
并且最终得到了
it and gotten a good
房价数据的最好拟合结果
fit to my data set of housing prices.
现在你可以用它来预测
And you can now use it to predict.
比如说 假如你有个朋友
You know, if your friend has a
他有一套房子
house with a
面积1250平方英尺(约116平米)
size 1250 square feet, you
现在你可以通过这个数据
can now read off the value
然后告诉他们
and tell them that, I don't
也许他的房子
know, maybe they can get
可以卖到35万美元
$350,000 for their house.
最后 我想再给出
Finally, just to give
另一个名字
this another name, it turns out
实际上 我们
that the algorithm that we
刚刚使用的算法
just went over is sometimes
有时也称为批量梯度下降
called batch gradient descent.
实际上 在机器学习中
And it turns out in machine
我们这些搞机器学习的人
learning, I feel like us machine
通常不太会
learning people, we're not always
给算法起名字
created has given me some algorithms.
但这个名字"批量梯度下降"
But the term batch gradient descent
指的是
means that refers to the
在梯度下降的
fact that, in every step
每一步中
of gradient descent we're looking
我们都用到了所有的训​​练样本
at all of the training examples.
在梯度下降中
So, in gradient descent, you
在计算微分求导项时
know, when computing derivatives, we're computing
我们需要进行求和运算
these sums, this sum of.
所以 在每一个单独的
So, in every separate
梯度下降中 我们最终
gradient descent, we end up
都要计算这样一个东西
computing something like this, that
这个项需要对所有m个训练样本求和
sums over our M training examples.
因此 批量梯度下降法
And so the term batch gradient
这个名字 说明了
descent refers to the fact
我们需要考虑
when looking at the entire batch
所有这一"批"训练样本
of training examples, and again,
这确实不是一个
this is really, really not
很好听的名字
a great name, but this is
但是搞机器学习的人就是这么称呼的
what Machine Learning people call it.
而事实上
And it turns out there are
有时也有其他类型的
sometimes other versions of
梯度下降法
gradient descent that are not
不是这种"批量"型的
batch versions but instead do
不考虑整个的训练集
not look at the entire traning set
而是每次只关注
but look at small subsets
训练集中的一些小的子集
of the training sets at the time,
在后面的课程中 我们也将介绍这些方法
and we'll talk about those versions later in this course as well.
但就目前而言
But for now, using the algorithm
应用刚刚学到的算法
you just learned, now we're
你应该已经掌握了批量梯度算法
using batch gradient descent, you
并且能把它应用到
now know how to implement
线性回归中了
gradient descent, or linear regression.
这就是用于线性回归的梯度下降法
So that's linear regression with gradient descent.
如果你之前学过线性代数
If you've seen advanced linear algebra
有些同学之前
before so some you may
可能已经学过
have taken a class with advanced
高等线性代数
linear algebra, you might
你应该知道
know that there exists a solution
有一种计算
for numerically solving for the
代价函数J最小值的
minimum of the cost function
数值解法
J, without needing to
不需要梯度下降这种迭代算法
use and iterative algorithm like gradient descent.
在后面的课程中
Later in this course we will
我们也会谈到这个方法
talk about that method as
它可以在不需要
well that just solves for the
多步梯度下降的情况下
minimum cost function J without
也能解出代价函数J的最小值
needing this multiple steps of gradient descent.
这是另一种称为正规方程(normal equations)的方法
That other method is called normal equations methods.
可能你之前已经
And, but in case you
听说过这种方法
have heard of that method, it turns
实际上在数据量较大的情况下
out gradient descent will
梯度下降法比正规方程
scale better to larger data
要更适用一些
sets than that normal equals
现在我们已经
method and, now that
掌握了梯度下降
we know about gradient descent, we'll
我们可以在不同的环境中
be able to use it in
使用梯度下降法
lots of different contexts, and we'll
我们还将在不同的机器学习问题中大量地使用它
use it in lots of different Machine Learning problems as well.
所以 祝贺大家成功
So, congrats on learning
学会你的第一个机器学习算法
about your first Machine Learning algorithm.
我们稍后将有一些练习
We'll later have exercises in
这些练习会要求你
which we'll ask you to
实现梯度下降
implement gradient descent and
希望大家能让这些算法真正地为你工作
hopefully see these algorithms work for yourselves.
但在此之前
But before that I first
我还想先
want to tell you in
在下一组视频中
the next set of videos, the
告诉你
first want to tell you about
泛化的梯度下降
a generalization of the gradient descent
算法 这将使
algorithm that will make
梯度下降更加强大
it much more powerful and I
在下一段视频中我将介绍这一问题
guess I will tell you about that in the next video.